

PAUL COWAN

Contract Software Developer ♥ GLASGOW, UNITED KINGDOM 07908771391

o DETAILS o

Glasgow, United Kingdom 07908771391 paul.cowan@cutting.scot

o LINKS o

linkedin

o SKILLS o

JavaScript

reac

nodejs

typescript

Angular

rxjs

HTML, CSS

redux

SASS/SCSS

d3/d3js SQL Server, MYSQL, POSTGRES

C#

ASP.NET MVC

RUBY

○ HOBBIES ○

Combat sports, boxing, MMA

PROFILE

I have been a developer for over 19 years. My most recent work has involved full stack development on single page javascript applications. I have used the main javascript MV* frameworks (angular, react, emberjs) along with backbone.js.

Reactis is my current favourite.

My company website https://cutting.scot/ is a server rendered react website, here is the source code.

My github repos can be found <u>here</u> and my public development blog can be found <u>here</u>.

Here is an example of react code I have written.

Here is an example of angular code I have written.

Here is an example of an emberis component I wrote.

I have this <u>pull request</u> committed into the emberjs source code.

I've been exploring <u>d3.js</u> for some time and you can see some examples of more complex graphs that I have had great fun creating <u>here</u>.

I have spoken regularly for the Glasgow <u>javascript users</u> group and for the Scottish developers. I have also spoken at the <u>DSL Devcon</u> conference at Microsoft Redmond in 2009 where I gave the <u>DSLs in the horn package manager</u> talk.

Before moving to Glasgow, I worked for <u>twentysixlondon</u> as a technical architect on the following online websites:

The Volvo Ocean Race, Waitrose, Closer online and Abercrombie and Kent.

I originate from Belfast N.Ireland where I worked for Fujitsu on mainly government projects.

■ EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Contract Software Developer at Waracle, Glasgow, United Kingdom

January 2019 – April 2019

Full stack development for an online web portal with azure serverless technologies including blob storage and azure functions.

- Angular
- rxjs
- HTML 5, CSS, sassTypescript
- Azuure (Blob storage, functions)
- Terraform

Frontend Developer Contract at BJSS - Disclosure Scotland, Glasgow

June 2017 - December 2018

Rewrite of the old disclosure Scotland online application forms for criminal record checks into a react frontend written in typescript. Worked on other frontend systems for processing the online applications.

- Reactjs with redux for state management
- Jest, enzyme for Testing
- HTML 5, CSS, sass
- Typescript

Full Stack Contract Developer at WIPRO - Lloyds Bank, Edinburgh

November 2016 - June 2017

Working on the Scottish Widows pension portal

- React including mobx for state management
- Jest for Testing
- HTML 5, CSS, Styled Components
- JavaScript
- Nodejs

Full Stack Contract Developer at City Holdings

March 2016 - November 2016

Various projects including invoicing portal.

- Angular
- C#
- ASP.NET MVC
- SQL Server
- HTML, CSS
- JavaScript
- TDD (Jasmine, MSTest)

Full StackContract Developer at Continuity2, Glasgow

September 2007 - November 2012

Often the only developer on the Continuity2 business continuity software suite.

- ASP.NET MVC (1.0 4.5) C#
- Backbone.js JavaScript
- SQL Server
- MSMQ
- Nhibernate

Full Stack Contract Developer at Twentysixlondon, London

March 2004 – August 2007

Working for a digital agency working on some reasonably sized websites such as waitrose and the volvo ocean race.

- C#
- ASP.NET

EDUCATION

Further Education Anniesland, Glasgow

October 2015 – June 2016

Degree: Scottish Higher Maths – B

REFERENCES

Richard McGlave from Continuity2

richard.mcglave@continuity2.com